welcome back to another shotcut video
欢迎回到另一个截图视频
editing tutorial in this video we'll be
编辑教程在本视频中 我们将
adding text as a text overlay on top of
将文本作为文本覆盖添加到
our video and also adding text title
我们的视频 还添加了文本标题
screens I'm actually remaking this video
屏幕我实际上是在重新制作这个视频
the last one I made I was having issues
上一次我做的是有问题的
with shotcut crashing when I was trying
当我尝试的时候 我的快捷键崩溃了
to do some of the animation and like
去做一些动画 比如
animating text having an move on the
使文本在动画上移动
screen the the reason was as someone
屏幕上的原因是作为一个人
pointed out on YouTube I was using an
在YouTube上指出 我使用的是
outdated version so the version I'm
版本已过时 所以我的版本
using now is the latest version the nice
Using Now是最新版本的NICE
thing about open source software is it's
关于开源软件的问题是 它
always continually being updated and so
总是不断地更新 所以
hopefully I haven't I'm actually just
希望我没有 我其实只是
remaking this for the first time I
我第一次重拍这部电影
haven't tested to see if the bugs are
还没有进行测试以确定这些错误是否
fixed but hopefully we don't have that
修复了 但希望我们没有这样的问题
same crashing issue we were having last
我们上次遇到的同样的崩溃问题
time so to add text it's actually a
现在要添加文本 它实际上是一个
filter so we bring a video into our
过滤器 这样我们就可以将视频带到我们的
timeline while it's selected in red we
以红色WE选择时的时间线
just click Add and it's a video filter
只需点击添加 它就是一个视频过滤器
it's just called text and that adds some
它只是被称为文本 这增加了一些
text by default it adds the timecode so
默认情况下 文本会添加时间代码 以便
if we hit play it just shows the current
如果我们点击Play 它只会显示当前
time of the video we can also we can
视频的时间我们也可以我们也可以
erase that we can do frame so it shows
删除我们可以做的框 这样它就会显示出来
the current frame rate of the video not
视频备注的当前帧速率
incredibly useful for most projects but
对大多数项目都非常有用 但是
there are some different things you can
你可以做一些不同的事情
just click here that are sort of
只需点击此处即可
variable to your video file you can also
变量添加到视频文件中 您还可以
obviously just type in your own text
显然只需输入您自己的文本即可
though so you say in my video and we can
尽管你在我的视频里这么说 我们可以
change the color of the text so if we
更改文本的颜色 这样如果我们
wanted to be a different color maybe we
想成为一种不同的颜色也许我们
didn't want it to be like this red here
我不想这里变成这样的红色
we can change the actual font by
我们可以通过以下方式更改实际字体
clicking here we can choose a different
点击此处 我们可以选择不同的
type of font that we like and that you
我们喜欢的字体类型 而您
can also change the font size in here
我还可以在这里更改字体大小
but I wouldn't recommend doing it that
但我不建议这么做
way to change the size you can either
更改大小的方法您可以
come down here and click and just change
下来这里 点击一下 就可以改变了
these numbers manually or you can resize
手动设置这些数字 或者您可以调整大小
here by coming in the top right or left
在这里 通过进入右上角或左上角
or bottom corner and resize it there's
或底角并调整其大小
also a handle in the middle you can move
中间还有一个手柄 你可以移动
the text around if you get it sort of
周围的文字 如果你得到它的话
maybe off screen or somewhere you don't
也许在屏幕外或者其他你不知道的地方
want you can always reset it by just
希望您总是可以通过以下方式重置它
coming over here and clicking this
来到这里 点击这个
little like reset button that just
有点像重置按钮 只是
restores everything to how it was before
把一切都恢复到以前的样子
so we have position and size there's
所以我们有位置和大小
also an outline that's set to zero right
还有一个设置为零的轮廓
now the thickness if we bring that up we
现在 如果我们把它提出来 厚度是
can see it gets this kind of black thick
可以看到它变得如此黑色厚重
outline stroke on the text and we can
勾勒出文本上的笔划 我们就可以
change that
改变这一切
color as well and and then matific dance
色彩也是如此 然后是精彩的舞蹈
I don't love it oh I always make that
我不喜欢它 哦 我总是做那个
mistake I hit the enter key which
我错误地按了Enter键
toggles between our project and our
在我们的项目和我们的
source so go back to the project
所以回到项目中去吧
everything's there if every if maybe you
一切都在那里 如果每一个 如果你
do the same thing if you hit Enter while
如果您在按Enter键的同时执行相同的操作
you're on this it'll everything goes
你在这上面 一切都会好起来的
away and you're like what's going on
离开了 你就像是发生了什么
here but it's because it takes you back
但这是因为它把你带回了过去
to source we need to go back to project
要找到来源 我们需要返回到项目
anyway so if we can now we can change
不管怎样 如果我们现在可以改变的话
this so the vertical lift if we go top
这就是垂直升力 如果我们登上山顶
it Orient's the text to the top middle
它将文本定位到中间上方
and bottom and that's if it's
和底部 如果它是
constrained in that orientation if we
限制在该方向上 如果我们
constrain it this way we can go left
这样约束它 我们就可以向左转了
right or center so there's multiple ways
向右或居中 所以有多种方式
to move this text around I would say
要移动这个文本 我会说
just leave everything maybe just I like
就把我喜欢的东西都留下吧
to leave it centered actually and then I
把它放在中心位置 然后我
can just move this box around and it
只需移动这个盒子 它就会
kind of behaves the way I think it
有点像我想的那样
should I shoulda show this first maybe
我是不是应该先展示这个 也许
because with the animation there's these
因为在动画中有这些
different presets here but it'll reset
这里有不同的预置 但它会重置
all the coloring and any changes we made
所有的颜色和我们所做的任何更改
to the font but if we go like slide in
字体 但如果我们滑进去的话
from bottom left and go back go to the
从左下角开始 返回到
beginning the text will animate in what
开头的文本将以什么形式进行动画
is this slide or slide in from bottom
这张幻灯片是从底部滑进去的吗？
not left this is just slide in from
不是左边 这只是从
bottom so the text sort of animates in
底部 这样文本就有了动画效果
there and we see that there was a slide
在那里 我们看到有一个滑梯
in from the here's slide in from left so
从这里滑入 从左侧滑入 所以
kind of the same thing so some different
有点一样 所以有些不同
ways that you can do that if you want to
如果你想的话你可以这样做的方法
make changes to that we'll touch on this
对此进行更改 我们将讨论这一点
more in a future video but we go to
在未来的视频中有更多内容 但我们将转到
keyframes and we can actually change
关键帧 我们实际上可以更改
here the speed that comes in so right
在这里 速度是如此的正确
now it comes in further quickly we can
现在它更快地进入我们可以
click on this handle here there's sort
点击这里的手柄 这里就是排序
of this black triangle shaded area so
这个黑色三角形阴影区域的
now it'd be much much slower as it
现在它会慢得多 因为它
animates in again we'll touch more on
动画再次进入 我们将更多地接触到
that that's under this keyframes tab not
位于此关键帧选项卡下 而不是
under the timeline it's under keyframes
在时间线下 它在关键帧下
okay one more thing we're gonna try and
好的 还有一件事我们要试一试
do so we'll keep this here but let's go
这样做吧 我们会把这个放在这里 但我们走
into add a title screen there's a couple
要添加标题屏幕 有几个
ways to do it if we go up to here to
如果我们走到这里 就能做到这一点
open other we can just open a color and
打开其他的 我们只需打开一种颜色
we can just choose right now it's
我们现在就可以选择它是
transparent we can choose like a black
透明的我们可以像黑色一样选择
color and then all of a sudden we have
颜色 然后突然之间我们有了
just this black in here we can bring it
只要这里是黑色的 我们就可以把它拿来
over to our playlist and then we can
到我们的播放列表 然后我们就可以
always just bring it down
总是把它拉下来
we have this yeah so we should be able
我们有这个 是的 所以我们应该能够
to bring this down and insert it into
把这个取下来并把它插入到
our video clip so I didn't do that in
我们的视频剪辑 所以我没有在
the right place but that's okay I'll
对的地方 但没关系 我会的
just erase this so now we have some some
只要把这个擦掉 现在我们就有一些
empty blackness right before our video
就在我们的视频之前 一片空白
and then it kind of jumps in to our
然后它就像是跳到了我们的
video here so we can get we can select
视频在这里 这样我们就可以选择
this clip we can go to filters we go to
这个剪辑我们可以转到滤镜 我们可以转到
add text and we can put text right onto
添加文本 我们就可以将文本放在
this clip just like we would if it were
这个片段就像我们如果它是
a video clip let me show you another way
一段视频剪辑让我向你展示另一种方式
to do it though if we delete this we can
要做到这一点 如果我们删除它 我们可以
also go to open other and we just go to
也去打开其他的 我们只是去
text what that does is by default it
Text默认情况下 它执行的操作是
opens up a background with text already
打开已有文本的背景
on it and we can put our own text so we
我们可以把我们自己的文字放在上面 这样我们
can say this is my video and then we
可以说这是我的视频然后我们
choose the color of the background this
选择此背景的颜色
time maybe let's do a darker blue color
时间也许让我们做一个更深的蓝色
and then we just hit OK and now we have
然后我们只需点击OK 现在我们就有
a well so this is just up here in our
A好的 所以这就是我们的
sources if we navigate away from it
如果我们离开它 就会有消息来源
we'll lose it so we can left-click and
我们会失去它 这样我们就可以左键单击并
bring the whole clip into our playlist
将整个剪辑添加到我们的播放列表中
in case we ever want to grab it again
以防我们想要再次抓住它
because now if we click up here we're on
因为现在如果我们点击这里 我们就是在
something out so we get back to it and
所以我们要回到正题上来
then we can drag it down into our
然后我们就可以把它拖到我们的
timeline and so now we have this text
时间线 所以现在我们有这个文本
I'm on the back of blue and someone
我坐在蓝色的后座上
brought up two when we touch on
当我们谈到的时候 带了两个
transitions with this ripple select or
使用此涟漪SELECT或
this ripple trim and drop this let sit
这波纹修剪和下降这让坐着
so if we move forward it'll just
所以如果我们向前推进 它只会
automatically push forward everything if
如果出现以下情况 则自动将所有内容向前推
this were not selected we would create a
未选择此选项 我们将创建一个
transition between these two and and
这两个与和之间的过渡
when bringing in Clips it behaves
当引入剪辑时 它的行为是
differently as well so play with
也是不同的 所以玩
toggling this on and off I think I
打开和关闭这个 我想我
didn't touch on that too much when I was
我没有太多地触及这一点 当我
going over that at the beginning yeah
一开始就复习一下是的
let's see what this looks like this will
让我们看看这会是什么样子
be I can fade crossfade transition with
是我可以淡入淡出的交叉淡出过渡
text anyway hopefully you found that
无论如何 短信希望你能找到
informative and as you can see we did
信息量很大 正如你所见 我们做到了
some we played with it nothing crashed
有些我们玩过了 什么都没有坠毁
so huge shout out to the shotgun
对着猎枪大喊大叫
developers for always continually
开发人员总是不断地
improving this software if you find the
改进此软件 如果您发现
software useful consider visiting shot
考虑访问镜头的软件很有用
cut the official website I'll include
删掉我要加进去的官方网站
the link in description of this video to
本视频描述中的链接指向
show your support for this software and
显示您对此软件的支持并
for the developers thanks for watching
对于开发者 感谢您的收看
catch you in the next video
在下一个视频中看到你